l aura **Marsh**

Front End Software Engineer Los Angeles, CA

marshlau97@gmail.com | 510 456 8670 | lauralynnmarsh.com | git:/lauramarsh | in:/laura-marsh-lm

Summary

Current Software Engineer at an AI SaaS startup. 1+ years experience post-university (2+ years total) specializing in frontend development and design. Computer/art nerd who loves VSCode, color theory, React, and enjoys modularizing ui components for reusability. Interested in pursuing a technically motivated work environment while learning new technologies, and forging a closer relationship with CI and testing tools.

Skills

- · HTML, CSS, JS ES6, SQL, JSON
- · React, Redux, Styled Components, Sass, LESS, Feathers JS, JQuery, Bootstrap, Django, Flask
- · Sublime Text 2, VSCode, Atom, Git, Adobe Photoshop, Balsamiq

Work Experience_

Beyond Limits AI Glendale, CA

Front End Engineer

May 2019 - PRESENT

- · Took charge of a time-limited project's frontend/UX design while completely reworking legacy UI.
- Developed high-performing UIs for various projects, delivered several past POC, MVP phases.
- Used ES6 JS, React, Feathers JS, Redux, Node to build large-scale single page applications. Interacted with MongoDB and PostgreSQL databases. Versioned using Bitbucket + Git.
- Collaborated with data scientists and industry representatives during requirements gathering/analysis phase to create AI software that solves mission-critical problems in the space and petroleum industries.

Capital Group, American Funds

Irvine, CA

Capstone Project Engineer

Apr 2018 - Sep 2018

- · Delivered a micro app with client-side features.
- Used vanilla JS and Google Maps, Alpha Vantage APIs to build tools that gathered user input for analysis, created and displayed a mock portfolio, located nearby office locations/financial advisors geographically.
- Defined basic application structure and routers using python & flask. Engaged in initial requirements phases to develop ux and site flow. Designed graphic visuals to help educate and maintain user interest.

TenantBase Irvine, CA

Front End Engineering Intern

Jun 2017 - Sep 2017

- · Increased visitor traffic to TenantBase's business real estate leasing site by ~10%.
- Collaborated with market researchers to incorporated SEO techniques including page speed optimization, internal linking and breadcrumbing, generating appropriate location-based search data
- Updated legacy Django site using Wagtail for database management and GeoJSON for dynamically generating available real estate listings within input geographic search parameters
- · Implemented feature flags to toggle different page templates for user feedback/testing.

Dell EMC Menlo Park, CA

Firmware QA Intern

Jun 2015 - Sep 2015

- · Worked for DSSD, a recently acquired and currently absorbed startup revolutionizing cloud storage server technologies and procedures.
- · Created test suites in Python to verify basic product firm/hardware operations. Updated existing suites to match new product requirements.

Projects

Moving Palettes

HTML/CSS, JS, React, Feathers JS, MongoDB

· A fun single-page React app that generates a selection of my favorite gifs and a corresponding randomized color palette. Designed for ease, aesthetics, and efficiency between database and client-facing UI.

FabFlix

HTML/CSS, JS, AJAX, JQuery, Java, SQL, Apache TomCat, AWS EC2

- \cdot A movie browsing full-stack eCommerce web application populated with XML data gathered from IMDB.
- UI includes fuzzy/full-text search, built following MVC architecture alongside a mirroring Android app.
- · Used MySQL DBs with stored procedures/external functions for data management alongside load balancing on master/slave db instances.

Education